(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T14:01:48.642839",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
自業自得、なんだよなぁ・・
"It's entirely your own fault..."
この夏も、これからも先も
"This summer and all the days to come,"
もっと、もっと輝くから
"I'll shine even brighter!"
わんつーで参拝！
One, two, and pay your respects!
みこみこみこ！いぇーい！
Miko Miko Miko! Yay!
ついに来たよ お待たせ！
The time has finally come, thanks for waiting!
待ちに待った？うへへ♪
Have you been waiting long? Hehe♪
電脳世界からやってきた
I've come from the cyber world,
ウソかわいけバーチャル巫女アイドル！
A somewhat cute virtual shrine maiden idol!
私はそう！エリート！ (エリート？)
That's me! An elite! (An elite?)
なんていったってエリート！ (えっへん！)
No matter how you look at it, I'm an elite! (Hmph!)
エリート巫女？(巫女？) エリートアイドル？(アイドル？)
An elite shrine maiden? (A maiden?) An elite idol? (An idol?)
そんなの百も承知の両方に決まってるじゃん
Obviously, I'm a hundred percent both!
いじわるも泣き虫もカミサマも！？
Meanies, crybabies, and even gods!?
崇められたら巫女パワーで
If you worship me, with my shrine maiden power,
幸せわけてあげてもいいんだよ？
I'll share some happiness with you, you know?
(みこちゃんはー？エリートです！)
(What is Miko-chan? She's an elite!)
みこみこみこみこで ほにゃふにゃにゃーにゃーにゃー♪
Miko Miko Miko Miko, honyafunya nya nya nya♪
さくらくるくるり さくらみこ (みこ！)
Sakura whirling and spinning, Sakura Miko (Miko!)
みこみこみこみこで むにゅむにゅむぐむぐ
Miko Miko Miko Miko, munyumuyu mugumugu
明日から本気出す！(エリートですから！)
I'll get serious starting tomorrow! (Because I'm an elite!)
みこみこみこみこで ほにゃふにゃにゃーにゃーにゃー♪
Miko Miko Miko Miko, honyafunya nya nya nya♪
金時はほにゃにゃにゃにゃ たぶん！
Kintoki is honyanyanya, probably!
幸せの太鼓 ポンポコリンリンリン！
The drum of happiness, ponpokorin rin rin!
みんな笑顔になあれ！
May everyone break into a smile!
わんつーで参拝！
One, two, and pay your respects!
みこみこみこ！いぇーい！
Miko Miko Miko! Yay!
ちょっとだけ休憩タイム
Just a little break time,
マイペースだけど許してね！
I go at my own pace, so forgive me!
実はこれも修行のうちです
Actually, even this is part of my training!
そんなわけはなくなくない…？
There's no way that's true... right?
私はそう！エリート！ (エリート？)
That's me! An elite! (An elite?)
嘘じゃないよ？エリート！ (えっへん！)
I'm not lying! An elite! (Hmph!)
エリート巫女？(巫女？) エリートアイドル？(アイドル？)
An elite shrine maiden? (A maiden?) An elite idol? (An idol?)
今日もかんかん頑張っていきましょう！
Let's keep up our hard work today too!
ココロ模様 移り色 雨の日も！？
Shifting colors of the heart, even on rainy days!?
問題ない！巫女パワーで
No problem! With my shrine maiden power,
それ天晴れパレード！願いじゃおうよ！
It's a splendid parade! Let's make all our wishes come true!
(チャンネル登録してくれやあ！)
(Please subscribe to my channel!)
みこみこみこみこで ほにゃふにゃにゃーにゃーにゃー♪
Miko Miko Miko Miko, honyafunya nya nya nya♪
さくらくるくるり さくらみこ (みこ！)
Sakura whirling and spinning, Sakura Miko (Miko!)
みこみこみこみこで むしのもどきさいやきめですたいやき
Miko Miko Miko Miko, fake bugs, worst kind of taiyaki
(ビビーンはNo thank you！)
(Bibeen is No thank you!)
みこみこみこみこで ほにゃふにゃにゃーにゃーにゃー♪
Miko Miko Miko Miko, honyafunya nya nya nya♪
ほにやぽにゃーにゃーにゃーにゃー（むにゃー！）
Honiya ponya nya nya nya (munya!)
カミサマもほにゃにゃにゃにゃ たぶん！
Even the gods are honi-nya-nya-nya, probably!
元気の呪文 みこ声マイマイ みんな笑顔になあれ！
The spell of vitality! Miko-voice maimai, make everyone smile!
ワンツーおまちがいなーい！
One, two, my bad—!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
にゃはろー！みんな楽しんでる？？！
Nyahallo! Are you all having fun??!
ここからはスーパーみここタイム！
From here on is Super Miko-Miko Time!
ぜーったいに遅れずに付いてきてね？！
Make sure you follow along without falling behind?!
みんなで一緒に お手を拝借！せーの、はいっ！
Everyone, put your hands together! Ready, go!
みーこ！みーこ！（みーこ！みーこ！）
Miko! Miko! (Miko! Miko!)
みこはエリート！（みこはエリート！）
Miko is elite! (Miko is elite!)
e l i t e ! (e l i t e !) エリート！エリート！イェーーーー！！
e-l-i-t-e! (e-l-i-t-e!) Elite! Elite! Yeeeeh—!!
ラストにもう一回張り切って行くよーーっ！
Let's give it our all one last time—!
みこみこみこみこみんで
Miko-miko-miko-miko-miko-min,
ほにやぽにゃーにゃーにゃーにゃー（むにゃー！）
Honiya ponya nya nya nya (munya!)
らくらくらり さくらみこ（みこ！みこ！）
Easy-peasy Sakura Miko (Miko! Miko!)
みこみこみこみこみんで
Miko-miko-miko-miko-miko-min,
ひよひよみょみょみょみょーが ぴょっかぴょっか（チャームポイントですから！）
Hiyo-hiyo-myo-myo-myo-myo-ga, pyokka-pyokka (because it's my charm point!)
みこみこみこみこみんで
Miko-miko-miko-miko-miko-min,
ほにやぽにゃーにゃーにゃーにゃー カミサマもほにゃにゃにゃにゃ たぶん！
Even the gods are honi-nya-nya-nya, probably!
命をのっけてく ポプクリディディ
Riding on life, pop-kuri-didi,
みんな笑顔になあれ！
Make everyone smile!
ワンツーおまちがいなーい！
One, two, my bad—!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
最後にもう一拝！みこみこみこみこみん イェイ☆
One final bow! Miko-miko-miko-miko-min, yay☆
はーい！ということでにゃっはろー！
Hii! So, nyahallo!
ホロライブ所属のエリート巫女アイドル、さくらみこと申します！
I am Sakura Miko, an elite shrine maiden idol belonging to Hololive!
ということで、今回はみこの3周年サード記念日のライブに来てくれてどうもありがとうございます！イェイ！
So, thank you very much for coming to Miko's 3rd anniversary live! Yay!
みんな見てるー？ということでね、
Are you all watching? So,
今回のライブのタイトルを「Shine more!!」というにタイトルに決めさせていただきました！イェイ！
I decided on the title for this live as "Shine more!!" Yay!
まあね、この、このね装飾にもありますように、今回は夏をテーマにしたライブとなっております。
Well, as you can see in these decorations, this live has a summer theme.
そしてもっと輝くみこちゃんは4周年目ももっと輝いていくぞ！ということで、今回ねライブも頑張って行きたいと思いますので、みなさん最後まで絶対見なやなー、よろしくおねがいします！
And Miko-chan, shining even brighter, will shine even brighter in her 4th year too! So, I'd like to do my best for this live too, so everyone, please make sure to watch until the very end, I'm counting on you!
ということで、本日はね、ゲスト、ゲストを呼んでいるんですよ！やったー！
So, today, we have a guest... a guest invited! Yay!
ということで、ゲストを呼んでいこうかなー！どうぞー！
So, let's go call our guest! Here they come!
今日もいいお天気だ 私のためだけ地球はグルグル回ります
Today's weather is so nice. Just for me, the Earth spins round and round.
よっこらのわっしょい 勉強なんてね 見て見ぬ行為が得意です
Heave-ho, yo-heave-ho, studying? I'm great at turning a blind eye.
それより海とか行きたいサマだ！ 愛々愛して i want you
More than that, it's summer, I want to go to the beach! Loving, loving, loving you, I want you.
恋してココイチ 感じて灼熱 ラブみーテンダーかき氷
Fall in love at Cocoichi, feel the scorching heat, love-me-tender shaved ice.
あっけらかん（そうとも言う）
Carefree (you could say that)
天才とは（紙一重）
A genius is (a fine line away)
海行きたい！（だがしかし）
Want to go to the ocean! (But however)
日焼けは恐ろしや…
Sunburn is terrifying...
かっとばせ夏が来た 期待のルーキー 夏休み？！
Hit it out of the park, summer has arrived! The rookie of expectations, summer vacation?!
恋い焦がれたら 全力アピール
If you're pining away, full-force appeal!
何様？ おつかれサマー
Which one? Good job, summer.
カッコつけない魅惑のラブストーリー ダーリン i love you（ホアホア）
An unpretentious, enchanting love story. Darling, I love you (hoa-hoa).
聖人君子もあなたも私も結局つまりは人間です
Saints, you, and I are ultimately humans after all.
早口言葉だ！バナナにバナナがバナナでバナナの恋バナナ
A tongue twister! Banana on banana is banana, a banana's love banana.
それよりキャンプに行きたいサマだ！BBQでバーベキュー
More than that, it's summer, I want to go camping! Barbecue with BBQ.
それから夜には花火をしようよ 二人で秘密のアイランド
And then at night let's do fireworks, just the two of us on a secret island.
あっけらかん（そうとも言う）
Carefree (you could say that)
天才とは（紙一重）
A genius is (a fine line away)
肉食べたい！（だがしかし）
Want to eat meat! (But however)
いわゆる直火焼き…
So-called open-fire grilling...
かっとばせ夏が来た 地球のテンション急上昇
Hit it out of the park, summer has arrived! Earth's tension soaring rapidly.
待ち焦がれる程 全力バケーション
Longed for to the max, full-force vacation!
何様？ おつかれサマー
Which one? Good job, summer.
ちょっと待ってとろけちゃそうよ ダーリン i need you
Wait a second, I'm gonna melt, darling, I need you.
全力バケーション
Full-force vacation
何様？ おつかれサマー
Who do you think you are? Good work, summer!
ちょっと待って とろけちゃいそうよ
Wait a minute, I feel like I'm melting away
ダーリン I need you
Darling, I need you
酸いも甘いもかぎ分ける 甘いだけです青二才
Sniffing out the sour and sweet, but I'm just a greenhorn
それよいいい あれい良いよいい
That's good, that's really good
天の川
The Milky Way...
からの頭
...from my empty head
かっとばせ夏が来た
Smash it out, summer has arrived!
期待のルーキー 夏休み？
The promising rookie on summer vacation?
恋い焦がれたら 全力アピール
If you're yearning, make a full-force appeal
何様？ おつかれサマー
Who do you think you are? Good work, summer!
カッコつけない魅惑のラブストーリー
An unpretentious, enchanting love story
ダーリン I love you
Darling, I love you
かっとばせ夏が来た
Smash it out, summer has arrived!
地球のテンション急上昇
Earth's tension skyrocketing
待ち焦がれた夏
The long-awaited summer
全力バケーション
Full-force vacation
何様？ おつかれサマー
Who do you think you are? Good work, summer!
ちょっと待って とろけちゃいそうよ
Wait a minute, I feel like I'm melting away
ダーリン I need you (ホアホア)
Darling, I need you (Hoa-hoa)
そろそろこの曲終わりになるから 空前絶後のよろしくね
Since this song is almost ending, best regards like never before!
おセンチメンタル 鋼鉄のメンタル それでも明日は筋肉痛
Sentimental with a steel mental, yet tomorrow I'll have muscle pain
制服のパンツ脱いでいくわ 私をしっかり信じてね
I'll take off my uniform pants, so believe in me firmly!
世界で一番こんなに楽しい夏の1日をありがとうね
Thank you for the most fun summer day in the world!
おつかれサマー
Good work, summer!
はーい、ということで！すばちゃんに来てもらいました！
Hi everyone, so! We had Subaru-chan come join us!
すばるだよ！よろしくね！
It's Subaru! Nice to meet you!
よかったね、ありがとう！
I'm so glad, thank you!
サインを生で見れて！おめでとー！
Seeing the signature live! Congrats!
おめでと、おめでと！
Congrats, congrats!
今回はね、ちょっと夏って感じのライブにしたので
This time, we made the live concert feel very summery,
すばちゃんかなと思ってましてね！
so I thought of Subaru-chan!
だってすばるだって初めてこうやってメンバーのライブにゲスト入れたから
Because this is the first time Subaru has ever been a guest at a member's live concert,
結構緊張しちゃったよ！
I got pretty nervous!
おめでと！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
ということで、まだね、ゲストがいますのでね！呼んでいこうかなと思います！
And so, we still have another guest! I think we should call them out!
おー！
Oh!
それでは！
Now then!
えっ、こわ！おそるおそるじゃん！
Huh, scary! You're so timid!
じゃあ、すばるちゃん！いってくるね！頑張ってね！
Well then, Subaru-chan! I'm going! Do your best!
ということで、みっくろね歌います！聞いてください！日本笑顔百景！
And with that, Mikurone will sing! Please listen to it! Nippon Egao Hyakkei!
よぉおおおおおおおおお!!!
Yo-000000000!!!
じゅげむ じゅげむ ごこうのすりきれ かいじゃりすいぎょの すいぎょうまつ うんらいまつ ぶらいまつ
Jugemu Jugemu Gokou-no-surikire Kaijarisui-gyo-no Suigyōmatsu Unraimatsu Buraimatsu
くうねるところにすむところ
Kūneru-tokoro-ni-sumu-tokoro
やぶらこうじのぶらこうじ ぱいぽ ぱいぽ ぱいぽのしゅーりんがん
Yaburakouji-no-burakouji Paipo Paipo Paipo-no-shūringan
しゅーりんがんのぐーりんだい
Shūringan-no-gūrindai
ぐーりんだいのぽんぽこぴーのぽんぽこなのちょくめいのちゃーわんそんけい
Gūrindai-no-ponpokopī-no-ponpokona-no-chokumei-no-chawan-sonkei
ちょいと お時間 いただきます
Taking a little bit of your time,
ご清聴ください 揃いました!
please listen closely. We are gathered here!
笑うことと かけまして
What do laughing and...
お祭り野郎と 解きます
...a festival guy have in common?
そのこころは? そのこころは?
What's the answer? What's the answer?
どちらも ハッピ(法被)になるでしょう
Both will put you in a happy (happi coat) mood!
お後がよろしいようで
And that's our cue.
笑おう 笑おう さあ 笑いましょう こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on, let's laugh, especially in times like these!
笑おう
Let's laugh!
泣いたら負けだ ヤケクソ 笑いましょう
Crying is losing, so let's laugh out of desperation!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも 乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人 笑おう
Overcoming ups and downs, the sweet and sour, bravo Japanese people, let's laugh!
どんな時でも なにクソ 笑いましょう
No matter the time, let's laugh in defiance!
ぐわっほは にょほほ
Guwahoha, nyuhoho
空気なんて読まずに 笑っとけ
Just laugh without reading the mood!
笑顔 笑顔 笑顔 笑顔
Smile! Smile! Smile! Smile!
笑う門には 福来たる!
Fortune comes to a merry home!
皆様、本日はようこそおいでいただきました
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
ここで一席!!
Now for a story!!
ねずみのお嬢が嫁に行って、じきに帰ってきたんで、
A mouse's daughter got married, and returned home soon after,
ねずみのおかあさんが、大変怒って、
so her mother got terribly angry and said:
「あんな、いいところへ、おまえ嫁いで 誰が嫌で出てきたんだい?」
"You married into such a wonderful place! Who on earth did you hate so much to come back?"
「いいえ、だーれも嫌じゃないんですけれど、ご隠居さんがやさしいんで、嫌なの。」
"Well, nobody was unpleasant... but the master is too gentle, and that bothers me."
「優しいなら結構じゃないかねぇ。」
"If he's gentle, isn't that wonderful?"
「でも、猫なで声ですもの。」
"But he uses a cat-coaxing voice."
忙しさに身を任せて
Surrendering myself to the busyness,
消えていくだなんて べらんめぇ!
fading away like that, nonsense!
笑おう 笑おう 笑えなくても 笑うしかないでしょ 笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, even if we can't, we have no choice but to laugh, let's laugh!
笑おう (ソイヤ ソイヤ) 口上上げて ひたすら笑いましょう
Let's laugh (Soya Soya), raise our chins and just keep laughing!
応仁の乱 大きんさいさ クリアして 現代日本人
Clearing the Onin War and all its grand scale, we are modern Japanese!
笑おう 未来永劫 グハハと 笑いましょう
Let's laugh, into eternity, laughing "guhaha"!
小娘のたわごとと 切り捨てないで
Don't just dismiss it as a little girl's nonsense,
しかめつら なんか 変な顔 笑顔を見たいから
scowling with such a strange face, because I want to see your smile!
笑おう 笑おう さあ 笑いましょう
Let's laugh, let's laugh, come on, let's laugh!
こんな時代こそ 笑いましょう 笑おう (ソイヤ ソイヤ) 泣いたら負けだ やけくそ笑いましょう
In times like this, let's laugh! Let's laugh (Soya Soya), crying means you lose, let's laugh in desperation!
波乱万丈 酸いも甘いも 乗り越えた あっぱれ日本人
Having weathered all of life's ups and downs, we're wonderful Japanese!
笑おう どんな時でも なにくそ笑いましょう ひたすら笑いましょう
Let's laugh, no matter what time it is, let's laugh defiantly, let's just keep laughing!
ぐわっはっは (わっはっは) よっほっほ (よっほっほ) 空気なんて読まずに笑っとけ 笑顔 (笑顔) 笑顔 (笑顔) 笑う門には福来たる!
Guwahaha (Wahahaha), Yohhohho (Yohhohho), laugh without reading the room! Smiles (smiles), smiles (smiles), fortune comes to those who smile!
はーい！ということで！
Hii! So that means...
イェーイ！すごいすごい！
Yay! Amazing, amazing!
すごい！初めて歌えてすごい嬉しい！
Amazing! I'm so happy we got to sing this for the first time!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そうなんだよ、ミコロネでさ、知って、初めてなの。
That's right, MikoCorone, we only just learned it recently.
そうなの！イェーイ！ミコロネで初披露！
That's right! See! Our first MikoCorone performance!
もうすごい嬉しい！駆けつけちゃった。
I'm so happy, I got ahead of myself.
ねえ、この曲ね、すごくね、あのミコロネで歌いたいなと思って選ばせてもらったの。
Hey, we really wanted to sing this song together as MikoCorone, so we chose it.
そう、知ってる！この曲大好きで。
Yeah, I know! I love this song so much.
そう、みこみこと一緒に歌いたいなと思ってたから、もうほんとすごい歌えて嬉しかったなー！
Yeah! I wanted to sing with Miko-miko, so I'm just so happy we could sing it!
みこもね、この曲はね、ころねの歌ワクでね、知ったんだよ。
And Miko learned about this song from Korone's singing stream, you know.
え、そうなの！？
Eh, really!?
そうなの！イェーイ！歌えてよかった！
That's right! Yay! I'm so glad we sang it!
ということで、はい、今回、もう一人ね、ちょっとね、また呼びたい子がいるなって思ってて、
And with that, there's someone else we'd like to invite out here,
お呼びします！すばーーる！
Let's call her out! Subaruuu!
呼べよ！呼べよ！呼べよ！
Call me! Call me!
すごい！なんか、いっしょくというか…
Amazing! It's like a crossover...
初めてのね、こんなミコロネのところに呼んでもらえたんだ、嬉しい！
I'm so happy you invited me to MikoCorone's first time!
いや待って待って待って待って！せっかくだからさ、写真撮りたいなと思って！
Wait wait wait wait! Since we're here, we should take a photo!
せっかくだからさ、写真撮影をね、したいなと思うんですけど、いいですか？
Since we have the chance, we'd love to take a photo, is that okay?
こんな感じでさ、え、あいーん！あいーん！
Come close to the camera like this, ehehe!
すぐ殴るんだから！かつあげですよ、かつあげ！
You hit so fast, it's extortion, extortion!
あれ、あの会場の皆ともね、撮りたいなと思って！撮りたい！
Oh, we also want to take one with everyone in the venue.
じゃあカメラ回してもらって、せーの！
Okay, spin the camera around, ready, go!
え、しゃがんで取る？こうやって座って？やったー！
Eh, squat down? Sit like this? Yay!
え、エモい！すごい！嬉しい！すごい！
Eh, emotional! Amazing! I'm so happy!
ライブだ！ライブだ！やばいやばいやばい！
It's a live! A live! Oh no oh no!
たいやき！たいやき！たいやき！たいやき！
Taiyaki! Taiyaki!
あとないたる？え、どうしようかな…
What about after-party? What should we do...
あ、いい！
Ah, great!
中に、中に見込みがあるよ！
There's so much potential inside!
どう？どう？
How is it? How is it?
お願いします
Please!
いけるか？いけるか？
Can we? Can we?
まえ、まえ
Front, front!
後ろ、後ろだ！後ろ、後ろ！後ろ出る！
Back, it's in the back! Back, back! It's coming out in the back!
どこだ？
Where is it?
それだ！
That's it!
ほら！ほら！あ、なんかさ、さっきの気持ちになるの
Look! Look! Ah, somehow it brings back that feeling!
いい感じ、いい感じ！
Feels good, feels good!
やった！ありがとーー！
Yay! Thank youuu!
え、かわいい！
Eh, so cute!
え、めちゃくちゃかわいい！
Eh, super cute!
すごいかわいい！
So adorable!
二人とも本当にきたか、ありがとね！
You two really came, thank you!
え、こちらこそ！
Eh, likewise!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
じゃあみこ、この後も頑張るんでね！頑張ってね！
Well Miko, I'll keep working hard after this too! Do your best!
お水飲んでね！しっかり頑張ってね！
Drink some water! Work really hard!
がんばります！
I'll do my best!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
ということで、え、み、みこのね、の、ニコスタミだー！
And with that, um, Mi-, Miko's, uh, Niko-stamina!
緊急ミッション サプライズをしろ
[Emergency Mission: Pull off a surprise]
え？
Eh?
クエスト？なんかクエストが発動してる！
Quest? A quest is triggering!
なに？なに？
What? What?
何が起きた？
What happened?
これはやばい気がします！
I have a bad feeling about this!
え、クエスト？クエストじゃなくて、え、やばい！
Eh, a quest? Not a quest, wait, oh no!
やばい！
Oh no!
クエスト！クエスト！クエスト！
Quest! Quest! Quest!
なんかあるよ！なんか！
There's something! Something!
クエスト？
Quest?
え、何？クエストって。なんかある！
Eh, what? A quest? There's something!
何？ちょっと、これ……
What? Wait, this...
なんか、クエストあって……
There's some quest, and...
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
え、待って！なんかくえす、
Eh, wait! Some ques-,
クエストが出たんだけど
A quest popped up
待って！
Wait!
なに？なに？
What? What?
なんだろね、みこみこ。これや。
I wonder what it is, Miko-miko. This is.
みこ、みこちクエストあって……！
Miko, Miko-chi has a quest...!
えー！？
Eee?!
なになに！？いいですか？ちょっと開けても
What is it?! Is it okay? Can I open it a bit?
開けて！開けて！
Open it! Open it!
リハでも何も言わなかったじゃん！
You didn't say anything during rehearsal!
やばー！待って待って待って待って、これちょっと！
No way! Wait wait wait wait, hold on!
待って、これちょっと、見せてもらってもいいですか？
Wait, can we show this a bit?
みこピーの皆さんがですね、みこちのために！
MikoP's everywhere, for Miko-chi!
えー！このね、ゲームの、あの、GT... GTAじゃない、GT……
Eh! This game's, um, GT... not GTA, GT...
グランド・セフト・オートのサインを貰ってきてくれたんです！
They got us autographs for Grand Theft Auto!
えー！？やばい！やばい！
Eee?! No way! Amazing!
えー！？やばい！待って待って！
Eee?! No way! Wait wait!
やばい！なんと！サンチョ、I love you GTA！
Amazing! What, Sancho, I love you GTA!
え、すごくない！？
Eh, isn't that amazing?!
これね、ほかにもね、これ、こっちもそうだよ！
Look, there's others too, this one as well!
えー！？いっぱいあるよ！
Eee?! There are so many!
まて、まって、いいの？
Wait, wait, is it okay?
ほら、3つあるよ、3つ！
Look, there are 3, 3!
やばい、やばい、やばいよ！
No way, no way, this is crazy!
すごい！すごい！
Amazing! Amazing!
みこち、今の気持ちをカメラにどうぞ！
Miko-chi, please tell the camera your current feelings!
GTA！I love you！アイラブユー！
GTA! I love you! I love you!
おめでとう！ありがとう！
Congratulations! Thank you!
え、これ、知らなかったよね？みこちもね！
Eh, you didn't know this, right? Miko-chi didn't either!
まじで知らなかった！
I seriously didn't know!
ガチでビビった！こっちでビビった！
I got genuinely startled! Got startled right here!
え、この後なんかあるの？
Eh, is there something after this?
え、ありがとう！大切にします！
Eh, thank you! I'll cherish it!
大切にしてね！
Cherish it!
大事にして！
Take good care of it!
でもね、みこみこ、ほら、まだね、あるからさ！
But you know Miko-miko, look, there's still more!
そうだよ、これからも（あるから）
That's right, there will be more
ちゃんとこうやって大事にしまっといて
Make sure to store it carefully
そう、いったんね、それ回収させてもらって
Right, once, let's have you hand it back
やだ！やだ！
No way! No way!
やだ、まだ持っとくから！
No, I'll keep holding it!
成長にね、成長にね！そうそうそう！
For growth, for growth! That's right!
そこに置いてほら！
Put it right there, look!
じゃ、すばるもこれ持って！
Well, Subaru, hold this too!
じゃあ、みこち、頑張ってね！
Well Miko-chi, do your best!
頑張るんだよ！頑張るんだよ！
Do your best! Do your best!
がんばえー！ありがとー！
You can do it! Thank you!
ええ！？
Eee?!
マジで！？
Seriously?!
はあ！
Haa!
びっくりなんですけど！
I'm so surprised!
ということでね、この後も頑張っていきたいと思います！
With that said, I'll keep doing my best after this too!
思います！
I will!
サンキュー！
Thank you!
ちょっと、やばい、動悸がやばい！
Wait, oh no, my palpitations are crazy!
単純な言葉 重ねてゆく
Simple words keep piling up
もっと 心は 素直で
Making the heart more honest
なんでもないような その笑顔が 明日を照らす光に
That casual smile of yours becomes the light illuminating tomorrow
ずっと 気づいていたんだって
I've always noticed it
この手に 抱えていたんだって
I've always held it in these hands
弾けた 声に 流した 答えが
The answer I shed in a bursting voice
今 そっと きっと 願いこめた
Now softly and surely is filled with a wish
ずっと まわる まわる 夢 の 中で 繰り返し 君と 踊った
Spinning and spinning on and on in a dream, I danced with you again and again
揺れる 景色 道 は 続く
The swaying scenery, the road continues
通り過ぎる 風 に 吹かれ
Blown by passing winds
何度も 超えて 行ける から 境界線 雲 かき分け 手を 伸ばした
Because we can cross the boundary line over and over again, I parted the clouds and reached out my hand
涙 は 今 浮かぶ空 に 預けて 走り出す の
Entrusting my tears to the floating sky, I start running
涙は今 浮かぶ空に預けて 走り出すの
Tears are now left to the floating sky as I start running,
並んで 見つけた 輝く光を手に
side by side, holding the radiant light we found.
輝く光を手に
Holding the radiant light in hand.
問題はいつも自分次第
Trouble is always up to you yourself.
さあ 未来を選んで
Now, choose your future!
こんがらかった糸ほどいたら
Once you untangle the tangled thread,
思いのまま 進もう
let's move forward just as we wish.
毎日冒険なんだって
Every day is an adventure,
奇跡は無限大なんだって
and miracles are infinite.
高鳴る想い
Beating feelings...
羅針盤のように 今 そっと きっと 導いてく
like a compass, gently and surely guiding the way now.
そうだ! めぐるめぐる波に乗っかって 風まかせ 君と笑った
That's right! Riding the spinning waves, laughing with you on the wind.
予想外は 想定内 間違いや 失敗も楽しんで
The unexpected is expected; enjoy mistakes and failures too.
踏み出したら見えた 可能性 行き止まりの壁壊して
Step out and see possibilities, breaking down dead-end walls.
まだ知らない
To a world we don't know yet,
世界 君と一緒なら 怖くないよ
if I'm with you, I'm not afraid.
わくわくしている 今が一番大好き
I'm so excited; right now is my absolute favorite.
はい! はい! はい!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
ゆっくり（ゆっくり） 焦らない（焦らない） 自分の（自分の）
Slowly (slowly), don't rush (don't rush), at our own (our own)
歩幅で行こう 大丈夫（大丈夫）
pace let's go, it's alright (it's alright).
心配ない（心配ない） 描いたもの 全部叶えるよ
Don't worry (don't worry), everything you drew will come true.
すっと まわる まわる 夢の中で 繰り返し君と踊った
Spinning smoothly in a dream, dancing with you over and over.
いつか君と約そくした 願いの架け橋を渡って 何度も
Crossing the bridge of wishes we once promised each other, over and over,
超えて行けるから 境界線
we can cross the boundary line.
掻き分け 手を伸ばした
Pushing aside, I reached out my hand.
涙は今 浮かぶ空に預けて 走り出すの
Tears are now left to the floating sky as I start running,
並んで 見つけた 輝く光を手に わくわくしている
side by side, holding the radiant light we found, I'm so excited.
今が一番大好き
Right now is my absolute favorite.
はーい、ということで、どうですか？
Hii! So, how was it?
見てみてみてみてみてみて！え、ただいまですね
Look, look, look, look! Um, right now,
みこちゃん、コラボカフェを、あの開催しておりまして、
Miko-chan is holding a collaboration cafe,
エリートカフェって言うんですけど、その時のね、こう、
called Elite Cafe. At that time, like,
なんていうのかな、ま、店長の証というか、そんな感じで、
how should I put it, like the manager's proof or something,
カチューシャをね、つけてもらいました！
I got to wear the headband!
どう、かわいい？
How is it? Cute?
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい、ということで、あの現在ね、お、え？何？何何何何？
Right, so, um, right now, oh, eh? What? What what what?
なの？え、何？
What is it? Eh, what?
え、ちょっと待てないんですけど。ビデオメッセージが届いてます。
Wait, I can't wait. A video message has arrived.
え？え？何これ？
Eh? Eh? What is this?
なんて？なんで来てんのお前？ちょっと、
What? Why are you here, you? Wait,
サクラコが...長く出ますけど...えっとなんだっけ、みんな楽しんでるか？
Sakurako... will appear for a long time... um, what was it, everyone having fun?
こっち側なんですよ、ちょっと待ってください。あ、なんとミコは、
It's on this side, please wait a minute. Ah, somehow Miko,
こっちの世界でも活動ができるように、
so that she can be active in this world too,
新しい姿を手に入れたんだよね。
she acquired a new appearance, right?
の、分身ってわけだね？
So this is my clone, huh?
ちょっと待て、お前！
Wait a minute, you!
なんで勝手にやっての？
Why are you doing things on your own?
しゅがーたお…
Sugar Tao...
しゅがーたおじゃねえ、お前！
It's not Sugar Tao, you!
まあかわいい、まあみこが元だからね、かわいいは当たり前なんだけど
Well, she's cute. Since she's based on Miko, cuteness is a given, but
やつが、あのね、みこと違うの、これはね、やつが勝手に、あの、分身をし始めたというか
unlike Miko, she started making clones on her own, or rather
なんか、いきなり出てきたりというか、みこ全然、知らないでしょ、こういうのなんて
she just suddenly appeared, and Miko had no idea about something like this
あ、ちょっと、こんなふうに
Ah, wait, like this
あ、いや、すごい飛べてすごい、飛べるように、待て、なんだこれ
Ah, no, flying so much, wait, what is this
なんか、おかしいって、待て、すごい飛んでる、活躍できるように、こっちの世界は平穏するって言ってたよね？
Wait, something's wrong, wait, she's flying so much, you said this world would be peaceful, right?
なんでって、バーガーめ！
Why, you burger!
め！
You!
おい、なんだよ、こら！いやー！
Hey, what is this, hey! No!
おっと、おい、おい、おい、おい！やば、やば、やば、やば！
Oops, hey, hey, hey, hey! Oh no, oh no, oh no!
じゃあねー！
See ya!
あ、
Ah,
やあー、あのー、
Yaa, umm,
いや、そうなんですね、ちょっと、まあみんなに言うのは遅れたんですけど
well, that's right. I was a bit late telling everyone, but
結構前から、なんか分身しそうだなっていう気配はありまして、なんか、こういうふうになりました。
for quite a while, I had a feeling a clone might happen, and well, this is how it turned out.
あのね、いや、違うんだよ、なんか今日もね、なんか勝手にあいつがさ、なんか秋葉原とかを歩いてましたけどね、みこ全く知らなかったんだよ。
You see, no, it's not like that. Today too, she was walking around Akihabara on her own, but Miko had no idea at all.
なんか、みんなにはもう知られてたみたいですけど、はい。
It seems everyone already knew about it, though. Yes.
まあ、そんな感じで、なんかみこの、ま、分身というか、今日のこの根源を固めたものみたいなやつが、
Well, with that said, something like Miko's, well, clone or rather, something that solidified the root of today,
ちょっと、まあ今後ね、まあ、おのずとねから、共に活動していくのかなって思いますけど、どういう形になるか分かりませんけれども、
well, going into the future, naturally, we'll probably continue activities together, though I don't know what form it will take,
まあ、あのみこだよ、あ、みこだよとか、なんか呼ばれてたけど、ま、呼び方は自由にしていただけて、
well, she was called "Miko-dayo" or something, but you're free to call her whatever you like.
ま、みこのあの、今日のこんなとこ80%固めたようなやつなんでね、今後もどうぞ、まあ、おてやわらかに、よろしくお願いいたします。
Well, she's the one who solidified about 80% of Miko's today, so please treat her kindly in the future as well.
ということで、もうなんか勝手にさ、ちょっと始めちゃったからさ、ちょっと、ライブのテンポが崩れたじゃねえか！
So, since she just went ahead and started on her own, didn't that mess up the live's tempo?!
ということで、ま、今後もね、この後もどんどん、あの、ライブやっていくので、みんな最後まで見てくれよな！
So, we'll keep doing more lives after this, so everyone watch until the end!
みこはこの後ね、ちょっとかわいい、衣装に着替えしてきたいと思います。かわいいまーす！
After this, Miko wants to change into a cute outfit. So cute!
それでは、お着替え行ってきまーす！
Well then, I'm off to change!
いっせーので 君とだけ！
Ready, set, with you alone!
もう少し眠りたいけど
I want to sleep just a little more,
もったいないよ 今日はSunday
but what a waste, today is Sunday.
楽しいこと やりたいこと
Fun things to do, things I want to do,
Wake up! 始めようよ
Wake up! Let's get started.
めくるめく季節 君と
In the turning seasons, with you,
次のステージへ
to the next stage!
声を合わせ 扉開けて
Matching our voices, opening the door,
駆け出せ迷わずに
running out without hesitation!
転んでも かっこ悪くても イイじゃない
Even if we fall or look uncool, isn't that fine?
Stand up! イメージもっと 重ねて行くその先で
Stand up! Building up our images further, beyond that point!
いっせーので 君とだけ！
Ready, set, with you alone!
ハイタッチ 手たたいて
High-five, clapping our hands,
奏でるメロディーを
the melody we play
合図に走り出せ Go!
at the signal, run out, Go!
君となら こわくない
With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手たたいて 重ねるそのメモリーは
High-five, clapping hand in hand, the memories we build together
明日へのエネルギー Yeah!
are energy for tomorrow, Yeah!
さあ行こうよ もっと先へ
Now let's go further ahead!
君となら Happy Lucky Life (ハピラキラ)
With you, Happy Lucky Life!
あの日見た夢の続き 追いつくその日まで
The continuation of the dream I saw that day, until the day I catch up to it,
涙なんて振り切るくらい もっとスピードアップ
enough to shake off tears, speeding up even more!
どんな未来になっても 後悔しないよ
No matter what future awaits, I won't regret it,
自分自身 選んだ道 踏み出せ迷わずに
stepping out without hesitation on the path I chose myself!
踏み出せ迷わずに
Step forward without hesitating,
落ち込んで 進めなくなった時は
When you feel down and can't move forward,
Wake up! 思い出す
Wake up! Remember
夢見た頃の 宝物を
The treasures from the days you dreamed.
手と手で 奏でる叶える 煌めく夢を 君とだけ！
Hand in hand, playing and making your sparkling dream come true, with you alone!
ハイタッチ その度に
Every time we high-five,
繋がっていく心から
From our connecting hearts,
一人じゃないことを そう
You made me realize
気付かせてくれたよね
That I'm not alone, didn't you?
ハイタッチ 手と手と重ねて
High-five, stacking our hands together,
奏でるそのメロディーが 世界に届くまで！ Yeah!
Until the melody we play reaches the world! Yeah!
この夢は続いてく
This dream will go on,
君となら Happy Lucky Live! (ハピラキラ)
With you, Happy Lucky Live! (Hapilakira)
くじいて歩けない日は
On days when you stumble and can't walk,
おんぶしてあげる君を
I'll give you a piggyback ride,
ほら見てそっちの方が 強く地面 踏み込める
Look, that way you can step on the ground even stronger!
巡り巡る日々を
Through the revolving days,
巡り夢見たステージへ 届くその日を見つめて
Gazing at the day we reach the stage we dreamed of,
起こそう 君とだけ！
Let's make it happen, with just you!
手と手を鳴らす度 小さなビッグバン
Every time we clap our hands, a little Big Bang!
無限のそのチカラを受けて 進め！
Receive that infinite power and push forward!
ハイタッチ 手と手重ねて 奏でるそのメロディーを
High-five, stacking hands together, the melody we play,
合図に走り出せ Go! 君となら こわくない
Give the signal and run out, Go! With you, I'm not afraid.
ハイタッチ 手と手重ねて 重ねるそのメモリーは 明日へのエネルギー！ Yeah!
High-five, stacking hands, the memories we build are energy for tomorrow! Yeah!
さあ行こうもっと先へ 君となら Happy Lucky Live! (ハピラキラ)
Now let's go further ahead, with you, Happy Lucky Live! (Hapilakira)
応援してくれているみんなへ
To everyone who supports me,
まだまだLIVEの途中ですが！
Even though the live is still ongoing!
今日はお祝いに来てくれて 本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to celebrate today!
今日8月1日はデビューして 3年目の記念日。
Today, August 1st, is my 3rd anniversary since debut.
去年の今日は休止していて みんなとお祝いが出来なかった。
Last year on this day, I was on hiatus and couldn't celebrate with everyone.
すごくすごく悔しかったけど…
It was so, so frustrating, but...
今こうして笑顔で みんなに感謝を伝えられるのは あの時支えてくれたみんなと 今まで支えてきてくれた
Being able to smile now and express my gratitude to everyone is thanks to everyone who supported me back then and up until now
すべてのみんなのおかげです。
and all of you.
最高の夏にしよう！
Let's make this the best summer!
そんな気持ちを込めての3周年LIVE、 楽しんでもらえてますか？
Putting that feeling into our 3rd anniversary LIVE, are you enjoying it?
たくさんの楽しいことも 悔しいことも 悲しいことも 一気にこれからもずっと
Many fun things, frustrating things, and sad things, all together forever from now on,
みんなと一緒に感じていきたい みんなと一緒にこれからもずっと 走っていきたい！
I want to feel them together with everyone, and keep running together with everyone forever!
これからもみんなにたくさん貰った分 笑顔をもっともっと、返せるように
To be able to return even more smiles for all the things I've received from everyone,
4年目も毎日頑張っていこうと思ってるから これからも見ててよねぇ！
I plan to do my best every day in my 4th year too, so please keep watching me!
みこと出会ってくれて本当にありがとう。
Thank you so much for meeting Miko.
みんなのことがだーいだいだいだい大好きだよ！
I love you all so, so, so, so much!
みこより
From Miko
はい、ということでね 中央のステージに来ましたよ！
Yes, so we've come to the center stage!
みんながいる！すごい！
Everyone is here! Amazing!
ということでね、あのここまでたくさん歌ってきたんですけど なんと残すところ、2曲になります！
So, we've sung a lot up to this point, but there are only 2 songs left!
みんなね、どうだったかな？ やっぱり夏はね、こう盛り上がったり ハッピーだったりするんですけど
Everyone, how was it? Summer is a time to get hyped up and happy,
今から歌う曲は こう、みこのとってもとっても思い出深い曲ですね。みこが初めて生放送をしたときに歌った曲です。
and the song we're going to sing now is a very, very memorable song for Miko. It's the song Miko sang when she first did a live broadcast.
あんときは、おちくちゅのいちゅって なんか、なんかあれだったんだけど、今回はちゃんと一緒に気持ちを込めて歌いたいと思います。
Back then, my voice was shaking and... it was a bit rough, but this time I want to sing it properly together with all my heart.
それでは、聞いてください。
So, please listen to it.
シークレットベース〜君がくれたもの〜
Secret Base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~
secret base～君がくれたもの～ 作詞・作曲：町田紀彦
[Song: secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~ / Lyrics & Music: Michihiko Machida]
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future
大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget my grand hopes
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
I believe we'll meet again in August 10 years from now
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
出会いは ふとした 瞬間
We met in a sudden moment,
帰り道の 交差点で
at an intersection on the way home
声をかけてくれたね 「一緒に帰ろう」
You called out to me, "Let's go home together"
僕は 照れくさそうに カバンで顔を隠しながら
I hid my face shyly with my bag
本当は とても とても 嬉しかったよ
The truth is, I was so, so happy
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, fireworks in the night sky bloom so beautifully, a little sadly
あぁ 風が時間とともに 流れる
Ah, the wind flows with time
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険も いろいろしたね
I was so happy and fun, we had so many adventures
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
In our secret base
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future
大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget my grand hopes
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
I believe we'll meet again in August 10 years from now
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」 叫んでいたこと 知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Hold back your tears, say goodbye with a smile, it's so sad
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
あぁ 夏休みも あと少しで 終わっちゃうから
Ah, summer vacation will end soon
あぁ 太陽と月 仲良くして
Ah, the sun and moon get along well
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩も いろいろしたね
Sad and lonely, we had various fights
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
In our secret base
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」 叫んでいたこと 知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Hold back your tears, say goodbye with a smile, it's so sad
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
突然の 転校で どうしようもなく
Suddenly transferred, without knowing what to do
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ
I'll write letters, I'll make calls
忘れないでね 僕のことを
Don't forget me
いつまでも 二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base forever
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して
With you, the end of summer, always talking
夕日を見てから 星を眺め
Watching the sunset, gazing at the stars
君の頬を 流れた 涙は ずっと忘れない
I won't forget the tears that flowed on your cheek
君が最後まで 大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'll never forget that you waved your hand so big until the end
だから こうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に…
So, like this, in my dreams, forever...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future
大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget my grand hopes
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
I believe we'll meet again in August 10 years from now
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」 叫んでいたこと 知ってたよ
I knew you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart until the very end
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Hold back your tears, say goodbye with a smile, it's so sad
最高の思い出を…
The best memories...
はい、ということで、どうでしたか？ みんなありがとう！
Yes, so how was it? Thank you everyone!
残すところ、1曲と…なりました！
There's only one song left... now!
この曲はですね
This song, you see...
まあ、今日、巫女がね、サプライズをもらったにしても
Well, even though Miko received a surprise today,
巫女が今度はみんなにサプライズをしようかなと思います。
Miko thought she'd give everyone a surprise this time.
なんと巫女ちゃんの進捗をこちらで発表しようかなと思います。
And I'd like to announce Miko-chan's progress right here.
皆さん聞いてくれますか？
Will you all listen?
では、
Now then,
聞いてください。
please listen.
花月ノ夢。
"Kagetsu no Yume."
時代（とき）を越え 今宵も願う
Crossing through time, tonight I still pray,
途切れぬ想い 届くようにと
hoping these unbroken feelings will reach you.
運命（さだめ）だとは 気付かないまま
Without realizing that it was destiny,
貴方の姿を探す
I search for your figure.
一夜（ひとよ）一夜（ひとよ） 追いかける夢
Night after night, chasing after this dream,
朽ち果ててしまわないように
so that it won't wither and perish,
ひらり ひらり 舞い踊りましょう
softly, softly, let us dance and flutter around.
晩に消えるまでは 口寄せ詠う
Until it vanishes at dusk, I chant our spiritual song.
この夢は 儚く揺れる
This dream trembles fleetingly,
永遠（とわ）に続くように願っても…
even as I pray for it to last eternally...
伝えたい 貴方だけには
There is something I want to tell you alone:
物語の結末を
the conclusion of our story.
月夜 重ね 辿り着く夢
Piling up moonlit nights, the dream I reach at last,
闇に染まってしまわぬよう
so that it won't be dyed in darkness,
桜 桜 咲き誇りましょう
cherry blossoms, cherry blossoms, let's bloom in full glory.
いつか貴方が振り向く その瞬間まで
Until the very moment you finally turn around,
一夜（ひとよ）一夜（ひとよ） 語り続けよう
Night after night, let us keep on talking.
幾千の時代（とき）を流れて
Flowing through thousands of eras,
ひらり ひらり 舞い踊る夢
softly, softly, a dream that dances around.
今宵 桜の下で Ah 口寄せ詠う
Tonight beneath the cherry blossoms, Ah, I chant our song.
はい、ということで、ここからはおしらせの時間です。
Yes, and with that, it's time for some announcements.
まずは、こちら！さくらみこ活動三周年記念グッズ、エリートな水着の抱き枕カバー！
First is this! Sakura Miko's 3rd-anniversary commemorative goods: the elite swimsuit dakimakura cover!
このあと22時から販売開始です。
Sales will begin at 10:00 PM!
こちらのイラストは、ばん先生に描いていただきましたよ。
This illustration was drawn for us by Ban-sensei.
とっても可愛いエリートな水着、みんな気に入ってくれたらいいな。
It's a super cute, elite swimsuit—I hope you all like it!
裏側は夏バテをしているみ
The back side features Miko suffering from the summer heat...
ここですね、
Look at this!
うつぶせになってます。
It's so lovely!
このだらしなない顔がなぜか、しっくりきてしまう。
This defenseless face just melts my heart.
数量限定バージョンには特典として、直筆サイン入りポストカードがついてきます！
Quantity-limited versions come with an autographed postcard as a special bonus!
今回は前回のばあい、いやそれじゃあ、またもや監禁されながら描かせていただきましたよ！
This time, even more so than last time, I had them draw it while being locked away!
そして通常バージョン特典には箔押しのサイン入りポストカードがついてきます。
And regular version specials include a stamped autographed postcard.
お次はこちら！
Next up is this!
7月29日から秋葉原にあるステラマップカフェさんにて、
From July 29th at Stellamap Cafe in Akihabara,
コラボカフェ「さくらみこ 3rd anniversary さくらみこのえりーとカフェ」は8月15日まで期間限定で開催中です！
the Sakura Miko 3rd Anniversary Cafe is being held for a limited time!
メインビジュアルはオルダ先生に、ちびキャライラストはトダ先生に描いていただきました！とってもかわいい！
The main visuals were drawn by Oruuda-sensei, and the chibi character illustrations by Tota-sensei—they're so cute!
コラボカフェに来れないよって方もしっかり通販もあるのでぜひ記念にコラボカフェグッズゲットしてね！
If you can't make it to the cafe, goods are also available for order online, so be sure to get yours to commemorate the event!
そしてなんと！こいつがエリートカフェに居座るみたいです！
And guess what? It looks like this little guy is actually going to be serving at the Elite Cafe!
みこおの1日店長のひには動き出すかも！？これは現地みこぴーのつやチェックするしかない！
Will Miko's mascot make an appearance during her day as cafe manager? All you can do is check the local Miko-P's posts!
あ、ちなみに店内は撮影オッケーです！でもみんなの顔は隠してくださいね。
By the way, interior photography is okay, but please make sure to hide everyone's faces!
コラボカフェの詳細やグッズの購入ページは概要欄に記載してあると思うのでぜひチェック！
You can find the cafe details and goods purchase page linked in the description below, so be sure to check it out!
そしてこのあとすぐメンバー限定放送を予定しているのでぜひこの機会にさくらみこのメンバー加入待ってるだぞーん！
And right after this, we're having a member-only broadcast, so I really hope you'll take this chance to join Miko's membership and wait for us!
いじょ、エリート巫女アイドルさくらみこでした！4年目もがんばるぞー！みんなついてきてね！
Alright, this has been Elite Miko Idol Sakura Miko! Let's do our best in our fourth year too, everyone come along with me!